Man:
Listen to a talk on a biology podcast.
Picture a creature that's smaller than a mouse, yet as territorial as a lion.
Does it sound like a cartoon character?
It's actually the real-life Scarlet Badis, a freshwater fish.
It's only about 2 cm long at most.
In the wild, it generally thrives peacefully in the slow-moving streams of India.
Because of its size and attractive coloring, it's also a popular choice for aquariums and fish tanks.
However, in captive environments like aquariums, males are more aggressive.
They'll chase and nip at other males if they encroach on their territory,
so it's crucial to include lots of vegetation.
Plants act as hiding places and borderlines between males' territories.
Now male Scarlet Badis are a vivid orangish-red, scarlet with light bluish stripes.
When a male isn't having a confrontation with another male in the aquarium though,
his scarlet is less bright, it can almost,
but not quite, resemble female coloring,
which is dull gray.
This could make it hard to tell the sexes apart, except if you can
see any scarlet at all on the fish, it's a male.
Plus, unlike in most fish species, males are also usually a bit larger than females.
And the other time a male Scarlet Badis shows his brightest coloring is during breeding season.
In aquariums, he can be observed doing a sort of dance to impress females.
Showing himself off, his dance also involves following the female around until she decides
whether to mate with him.